Finding Aid for the Dianne Post Papers LSC.2228
UCLA Library Special Collections
Dianne Post papers
1980-2008
LSC.2228
UCLA Library Special Collections
1.8 linear feet (2 boxes, 1 carton)
Dianne Post is a lawyer who specializes in developing policy and programmatic reform on issues related to gender equality. Also active in the lesbian feminist movement, she organized cultural and political activities in Arizona to challenge domestic violence and advocate for the rights of the LGBT community. This collection contains organizational documents from activist organizations throughout Arizona specifically focused on domestic violence and gay and lesbian issues. Included are materials related to the planning of the first women's music festival in Arizona as well as recordings of lesbian and women's music. Also included are legal documents authored by or used by Dianne Post, articles published by and about Dianne Post, correspondence, and ephemera.
Post, Dianne
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, transfer, 2014. Original provenance unknown.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7404727
Biography
Dianne Post (born 1947) is a lawyer who has worked in over fourteen countries over the past twenty six years. She has contributed to the design and implementation of legal policies and reform initiatives related to gender equality. Post works with vulnerable populations in developing, transitional and developed countries.
Post consults on international cases, and has worked with the United Nations, the Inter-American Commission on Human Rights and the European Court of Human Rights. She specializes in issues related to violence against women and children including sex-trafficking, pornography, and domestic violence.
Also active in the lesbian feminist movement, she was the first to produce a women's music festival in Arizona, the Arizona Womyn's Music Festival.
Scope and Content
This collection contains organizational documents from activist organizations throughout Arizona specifically focused on domestic violence and gay and lesbian issues. Included are materials related to the planning of Arizona Womyn's Music Festival (the first women's music festival in Arizona) as well as recordings of lesbian and women's music. Also included are legal documents authored by or used by Dianne Post, articles published by and about Dianne Post, correspondence, and ephemera.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials arranged by subject.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.; Post, Dianne -- Archives.; Human rights workers--United States--Archives.; Lesbian activists--United States--Archives.; Women lawyers--United States--Archives.
- Feminist publications, 1981-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Assorted feminist publications, including the last issue of Off Our Backs and Lavender Moon.
- Sonia Johnson: Presidential candidate, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Fundraising materials, clippings and interview on one cassette tape with lesbian presidential candidate Sonia Johnson.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIO MATERIALS: Audio materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
- Arizona Womyn's Music Festival, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Flyers, maps, programs and festival information, which Post helped organize.
- Subject files: Domestic violence, 1989-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Copies of clippings and publications regarding domestic violence.
- Clippings of articles by Dianne Post, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Articles and op-eds written or contributed to by Dianne Post in various magazines and newspapers.
- LTN Newsletter, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Flyers, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Flyers for events, readings and talks.
- Assorted newsletters, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Newsletters for organizations including Valley Community Women, Women's Center Inc. and Arizona Women's News.
- Clippings: Coverage of Dianne Post, 1992-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Clippings of newspaper and magazine stories concerning the activism and professional life of Dianne Post.
- Valley of the Sun Gay and Lesbian Community Center, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Board meeting minutes, communication, reports, programming discussions for the Valley of the Sun Gay and Lesbian Community Center.
- Arizonans for Fairness Coalition, Inc., 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folders 1-2, Box 1, Folder 11)
  Financial documents, articles of incorporation, press releases, promotional ephemera, and other documents related to the formation and work of Arizonans for Fairness Coalition, Inc.
- Correspondence, circa 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lesbian Resource Project, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Newsletter and flyer from the Lesbian Resource Project, an Arizona lesbian social and educational group. Also includes a certificate of appreciation for Post.
- Legal publications, 1996-2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Publications having to do with legal news, philosophies and discussions.
- Legal documents: New Times Inc. v. Women Take Back the Night, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Depositions, briefs, summaries and communication surrounding this case. Women Take Back the Night, of which Post was a member, was an organization dedicated to protesting against domestic violence.
- Legal documents: Lesbian couple child custody cases, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Briefs, summaries, trial documents and depositions having to do with several child custody cases between lesbian couples.
- State Bar of Arizona: Gay and Lesbian Task Force Report, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Bound copy of the State Bar of Arizona's report by the Gay and Lesbian Task Force.
- Pro-choice materials, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folders 9-10)
  Correspondence, news clippings and notes having to do with Dianne Post's (and others') activism and protest concerning the appointment of anti-choice Board Members to both Planned Parenthood and the Arizona Human Rights Fund.
- Assorted materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Business cards and personal items.
- Published works and ephemera, 1980-2008 (Box 3)
  Includes three t-shirts from the Arizona Womyn's Music Festival, 6 CDs and 29 audiocassettes containing recordings by lesbian musicians, several buttons and pins, and a number of published books:
  Elaine Mikels - Just Lucky I guess Ruthann Robson - Lesbian (Out)Law Daphne Scholinski - The Last Time I Wore a Dress Karen Louise - Foster Child Karen Dale Wolman - Rites of First Blood Susan Hawthorne - Wild Politics Marilyn Murphy - Are You Girls Traveling Alone? Joann Drury - The Other Side of Silence Becky Birtha - Lover's Choice Jennifer Kelly - Zest for Life Olivia Free Woman - The Incident at New Providence Olivia Free Woman - Selected Works The Practical Lawyer - Vol. 33, 37
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.